Andrei Karalevich

Address: 5211 Pacific Concourse Drive, Los Angeles, CA, 90045, United States

Email: karalevichandrei@gmail.com

Mobile: (253) 212-8501

Website: https://akaralevich.netlify.app/ **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/a112k/

I am a dynamic and creative Front-End engineer with 3 years of experience in web development for high-volume

companies. I am full of energy and eager to contribute to the dev team by sharing top-notch coding skills.

Professional Experience

Frontend Software Engineer

Nexon America, Los Angeles, CA.

From July 2022 to March 2023

- -Completely rebranded the company's affiliate website "Nexon Game Card" which increased gift card sales and generated an additional annual revenue.
- -Expanding the capabilities of the internal tool for managing and testing user data for more efficient interaction with the database. Which reduced server costs and saved \$0.2 million per year.
- -Developed a microsite for a seasonal company event that resulted in an additional 70,000 users within a month.

Frontend Software Engineer

Wargaming, Saint Petersburg, Russia.

From May 2021 to March 2022

- -Created a complex internal UI component, eliminating the need to buy a license from a third-party tool. What saved the company \$15k a year.
- -Components have been developed and implemented that allows the player to control the progress of ship construction in the game client. The work was done as part of a seasonal event with high user interest and brought in 20% of the annual income of World of Warships.
- -A set of measures was taken on one of the applications: updated the code base, implemented TypeScript, increased test coverage to 90%, add lazy loading of the bundle. This reduced the web page loading time by 4 seconds and significantly increased the speed of implementation of the new functionality and the application's stability.

Frontend Software Engineer

LeverX Group, Minsk, Belarus.

From November 2020 to May 2021

- -Developed a new way to create customer preference tracking tags, which increased our customers' revenue by 6%.
- -I solved the application scalability problem by replacing the side effect manager with a more appropriate one. This made it possible to introduce new functionality and increase the company's annual income.
- -I did an impressive job of clearing the accumulated technical debt, which greatly helped the team to focus on the development of new features.

Frontend Software Engineer

Freelance, Belarus.

From October 2019 to November 2020

- -I was responsible for creating a Frontend part of the climate-tracking system.
- -Carried out a set of measures to optimize the client side of the application: integrated the ServiceWorker, set up a Webpack that accelerated the loading of the application by 20% and wrote unit tests to increase the application's stability.

Engineer

Belarusian Nuclear Power Plant, Belarus.

From July 2016 to July 2020

- The position is not relevant to a software engineer, please contact me for more information.

Education

Belarusian National Technical University.

From September 2011 to July 2016

Bachelor of Engineering, Chemical

Additional Skills

-JavaScript, React, Vue, TypeScript, Redux, Jest, Axios, Webpack, HTML, Canvas, CSS, GIT, GitHub, GitLab, ESLint, Babel, Storybook, Node.js, Express.js, Docker, MongoDB, GraphQL, Python, RxJS, jQuery, Flutter, Firebase, WebSocket.